Finding Aid for the Alfred H. Bartles Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- DETAILED CONTAINER LIST
  - Series A: Musical compositions—Manuscripts
    - Series A: Musical compositions—Manuscripts
      - Subsubseries 1: Works for large ensembles. Original compositions and arrangements
        - Large ensemble. Arrangements and transcriptions Folder (Box 5)
          - “Allegro”, Nov. 15, 1992: for solo violin and chamber orchestra; by G. H. Fiocco, arr. Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score and photocopy of published source score, photocopies of parts; includes contracts with Mediaphon GmbH (Box 5, Folder 4)
          - “Captain Ahab”, Feb. 5, 1959: for jazz ensemble; manuscript of score (concert pitch) (Box 5, Folder 5)
          - “Dancing on the Ceiling”, Mar. 30, 1952: for jazz ensemble; manuscript of score (concert pitch) (Box 5, Folder 6)
          - “Deep in a Dream”, Jun. 1955: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred H. Bartles; corrected manuscript of score and incomplete parts; computer-printed copy of score and computer-printed copies of parts (ca. 2000) (Box 5, Folder 7)
          - “Devil and the Deep Blue Sea”, Dec. 12, 1958, with additions from Feb. 15,1961: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred H. Bartles “for Del in Houston”; manuscript of score (Box 5, Folder 8)
          - “Granada”, Jun. 2, 1960: for jazz ensemble; by Augustin Lara, arr. Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 5, Folder 9)
          - “Green Dolphin Street”, Sept. 16, 1960: for jazz ensemble; arr. A. H. Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 5, Folder 10)
          - “Guys and Dolls - Opener”, Aug. 6,1962: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 5, Folder 11)
          - “Hello Dolly!”, Apr. 21, 1965: for orchestra; arranged by Alfred Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 5, Folder 12)
        - Large ensemble. Arrangements and transcriptions Folder (Box 6)
          - “I’ll Take Romance”, Mar. 28,1958: for strings; arr. Alfred Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 6, Folder 1)
          - “I’m Old-Fashioned”, Feb. 8, 1960: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred H. Bartles “for Del in Monroe, La.”; manuscript of score (Box 6, Folder 2)
          - “Jordu-Daa Houd-Had-itN”, Nov. 27, 1960: for jazz ensemble; by Duke Jordan, Clifford Brown, and Alfred Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 6, Folder 3)
          - “Lady Be Good! (cause you’re in fora surprise!)”, Jul. 7, 1959: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 6, Folder 4)
          - “Marionette”, [n.d.]: for jazz ensemble; incomplete manuscript sketch (Box 6, Folder 5)
          - “Mr. Lucky: Theme from the TV Show”, [n.d.]: for jazz ensemble; by Henry Mancini, arr. A. H. Bartles; incomplete manuscript of score (Box 6, Folder 6)
          - “Out of This World”, Mar. 27-28, 1961: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred Bartles; manuscript of score; manuscript of revised version of score (Jun. 4, 2001) with computer-printed copies of score and parts (Box 6, Folder 7)
          - “First Rhapsody: for Violoncello and Orchestra”, Dec. 14,1988-May 26,1989: by Bêla Bartok, orchestration adapted for cello by Alfred H. Bartles; movements: Lassu - Friss; manuscript of score, and published miniature score of source original (Box 6, Folder 8)
          - “First Rhapsody: for Violoncello and Orchestra”, Dec. 14,1988-May 26,1989: by Bêla Bartok, orchestration adapted for cello by Alfred H. Bartles; movements: Lassu - Friss; manuscripts of wind parts, and computer-printed copies of string parts (Box 6, Folder 9)
          - [Second Rhapsody], [ca. 1990?]: incomplete transcription for cello and piano; by Bêla Bartok, transcribed by Alfred H. Bartles; incomplete manuscript (Box 6, Folder 10)
          - “Sometimes (Theme)”, Mar. 5,1973: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Large ensemble. Arrangements and transcriptions Folder (Box 6A)
          - “Sonata for Chamber Orchestra: Opus One”, Jan. 23-May 7,1984: by Alban Berg, orchestrated by Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score, photocopy of score with corrections; includes reference piano score (U.E. no. 8812) (Box 6A, Folder 1)
          - “Sonata for Chamber Orchestra: Opus One”, Jan. 23-May 7,1984: by Alban Berg, orchestrated by Alfred H. Bartles; manuscripts of parts and selective photocopies with bowings, and list of corrections from Mar. 1992 (Box 6A, Folder 2)
          - ‘The Song is You”, [n.d.]: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred H. Bartles; incomplete manuscript of close score (Box 6A, Folder 3)
          - “Spinnenlied, op. 67, Nr. 4”, Apr. 27-Nov. 12, 1987: for piccolo trumpet and string chamber orchestra; by Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, adapted by Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score and parts; photocopy of earlier draft with corrections in red pen (Box 6A, Folder 4)
          - ‘Taps Miller”, Jan. 27, 1969: for jazz ensemble; manuscript of score (Box 6A, Folder 5)
          - ‘They All Laughed (But Who’s Got the Last Laugh Now)”, Mar. 26,1961: for jazz ensemble; arr. Alfred Bartles; manuscript of score (Box 6A, Folder 6)
          - “Yardbird Suite”, Apr. 4, 2000: for jazz ensemble; by Charlie Parker, arr. Alf Bartles; manuscript of score; computer-printed copies of score and parts (Box 6A, Folder 7)
  - Series A: Musical compositions—Manuscripts
    - Subseries 1: Single works
      - Subsubseries 2: Works for solo/chamber ensemble
        - Solo/Chamber ensemble. Original works (Box 7)
          - [10 untitled sketches], various dates: lead sheet, manuscript (Nov. 27, 2002); lead sheet by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred H. Bartles, manuscript (Jun. 18-23, 1985); “for Nathan M. Emahiser,” incomplete keyboard manuscript sketches (Oct. 28, 2001); “For Isabel,” piano manuscript (May 3, 1970), theme used later in The Little Prince; computer-printed incomplete sketch of alto saxophone part to Jazz Waltzes, Noble andSentamental [i.e., Sentimental]; unidentified manuscript of cello part (Mar. 22, 1992), untitled sketch for solo piano [n.d.], “No I Music (?) for Piano”, “written for and dedicated to my small friend Martha” (Dec. 1952); unidentified work for two pianos (Nov. 22, 1980); jazz arrangement of “Alone Together” for solo piano, [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 1)
          - “And There was Light”, Feb. 20, 1969-Mar. 5, 1969: incidental music for piano solo; manuscript, program from associated eurythmy demonstration, and selected narrator texts (Box 7, Folder 2)
          - “Ballad for ‘Cello and Piano”, [n.d.]: arranged by the composer from the Ballad for Solo ‘Cello and String Chamber Orchestra; manuscript of score (Box 7, Folder 3)
          - “Beersheba Neo-Baroque Suite”, Apr. 9,1974: for tuba and cello/euphonium/trombone; one corrected manuscript, and note to engraver (Box 7, Folder 4)
          - “Byzantine Resurrection Hymn”, Jun. 2, 1997: for three trumpets; manuscript (Box 7, Folder 5)
          - “Cadenza for Vivaldi: Concerto in C Minor for 2 Violins”, Jan. 3,1994: manuscript (Box 7, Folder 6)
          - “Ceremonial Music for Organ”, Mar. 20,1969: manuscript (Box 7, Folder 7)
          - “Ceremonial Music for Trumpet in Bb and Organ”, Jun. 21,1971: arrangement of “Ceremonial Music for Organ”; manuscripts of score and part, corrected photocopies of score and part, and computer-printed copy of part (Box 7, Folder 8)
          - “Cookeville Neo-Classical Trio”, Jan. 6, 1976: “for two tubas and euphonium (with Three (3) Eyeglasses Obligatto)”; manuscript of score (Box 7, Folder 9)
          - “Duo for Violin and Cello”, Sept. 26, 1983-Jun. 20, 1984: manuscript of score and photocopy with additional fingerings (Box 7, Folder 10)
          - “Elegy for Tuba and Piano”, Feb. 12,1964: manuscript of score, two computer-printed copies of score, one with pencil revisions, and two computer-printed copies of parts, one with pencil revisions for cello, with Elegy for Bass Trombone and Piano, revised Dec. 28, 1968, arrangement of the piano and tuba version; manuscript of score and part (Box 7, Folder 11)
          - “Fanfare”, Oct. 1, 1980: for 6 trumpets in B-flat and two timpani; manuscript of score (Box 7, Folder 12)
          - “Fishin”‘, Apr. 10, 1998: lead sheet; theme used later in Three for Two; photocopy of manuscript and text of lyrics (Box 7, Folder 13)
          - “Fugue for Counterpoint 357”, Jan. 30, 1954: written for Fall Semester 1953-54 Paul Fontaine course at Ohio University, Athens, Ohio; manuscript keyboard score with indications for orchestral scoring in regular and red pencil (Box 7, Folder 14)
          - “Homage (to B.E.)”, Jan. 9,1999: for piano; manuscript, with “Homage (to B.E.)”, Apr. 15, 1999: for cello and piano, revision of the version for solo piano; manuscript of score and unbound corrected photocopy (Box 7, Folder 15)
          - “Jazz Triptytch [i.e., Triptych]: Three Settings for Piano”, Mar. 14,1975: movements: Bossa Nova - Ballad- Waltz; photocopy of manuscript (Box 7, Folder 16)
          - “Juliana”, Oct. 3, 1984: lead sheet; 2 photocopies of manuscript, 1 with corrections (Box 7, Folder 17)
          - “Lament, Variations & Metamorphosis for Woodwind Quintet”, Jan. 27,1970: for wind quintet; manuscript of score and parts (Box 7, Folder 18)
          - ‘The Little Prince”, Jan. 10-24, 1997: incidental music to the story by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry; for violin, cello, and piano; copy of narrated text, manuscript of score, manuscripts of corrected pages, and comb-bound photocopy (Box 7, Folder 19)
          - “Lyric Poem”, Sept. 9, 1981-Aug. 27, 1982: for violin and piano; manuscript of score and part, corrected photocopy of score (Box 7, Folder 20)
          - “Lyric Poem”, Sept. 9, 1981-Aug. 27, 1982: for violin and piano; bound photocopy of violin part, 6 computer-printed versions of score, most with corrections, computer-printed copy of part (Box 7, Folder 20a)
          - “Nanabush and the Chickadees”, Oct. 4, 1978: incidental music; for oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, and piano; corrected photocopy of score, photocopy of piano reduction, and photocopies of wind parts (Box 7, Folder 21)
          - “Night Sonatina”, Dec. 31, 1963: for unaccompanied treble clef instrument; manuscript (Box 7, Folder 22)
            Note: Later published under the title Sonatina for trumpet unaccompanied
        - Solo/Chamber ensemble. Original works (Box 8)
          - “Piano Quartet”, Aug. 21-Nov. 5, 1967: for violin, B \> clarinet (or viola), cello, and piano; manuscript of score and all parts (Box 8, Folder 1)
          - “Prologue to Tolkien”, “ Epilogue to Tolkien”, Aug. 27-28,1978: for piano; 2 photocopies of manuscript (Box 8, Folder 2)
          - “Etüden und Vortragsstücke für Violoncello, mit und ohne Klavierbegleitung, für fortgeschrittene Anfänger in ersten, vierten, zweiten und dritten engen Lage = Recital Pieces and Etudes for the Advanced Beginning ‘Cellist in First, Fourth, Second and Third Closed Position, with and without Piano Accompaniment”, ca. 1986-1994, copyright 1994: consists of three volumes of pieces with titles in both German and English (Box 8, Folder 3-10)
            “Etüden und Vortragsstücke für Violoncello, mit und ohne Klavierbegleitung, für fortgeschrittene Anfänger in ersten, vierten, zweiten und dritten engen Lage = Recital Pieces and Etudes for the Advanced Beginning ‘Cellist in First, Fourth, Second and Third Closed Position, with and without Piano Accompaniment”, ca. 1986-1994, copyright 1994: consists of three volumes of pieces with titles in both German and English:
            Heft I: Prelude (Hommage àJ.S. Bach) [solo] - Melodien zur Einführung in die vierte Lage [solo] - Melodien auf 2 Saiten in der vierten Lage (movements: Der lustige Vogel; Lied der Hirten in der Abenddämmerung; Das übermütige Pony) [solo] - Die Eichhörnchen [acc] - Zwergenhöhle [solo] - Die Bärenfamilie [solo] - See-Idylle [solo] -Versteckspiel [solo] - Verfolgungsjagd [solo] - Blätter im Wind [acc] - Abschied vor einer Seereise [solo] - Moby Dick [acc] - Die Geschichte eines Schmetterlings [acc] -Fliegende Fische [acc] - Spazieren in böhmischen Gebirgen [acc] - Dionysischer Tanz [acc]
            Heft II: Springbrunnen [solo] - Wogendes êhrenfeld [acc] - Die kleine griechische Ziegenhirtin [solo] - Herbstwind [solo] - Bourrée [acc] - La petitesse [acc] -Tutenchamun [solo] - Dorische Säulen [acc] - Theseus: Sein Weg aus dem Labyrinth [acc] - Das Spinnrad [solo] - Praeludium [solo] - Heimweh [acc] - Fantasiestück [acc] -Indianerlagerfeuertanz [acc]
            Heft III: Schätze! - Winter auf Island - Sonnenaufgang am Fjord - Irisch Air -Treue Freundschaft - Whyriigig - Gladiatoren Marsch - The Honey Bee Rag - Spielende Delphine - Tempo di sicilienne - Perpetuo moto - Barcarolle
          - —Heft I; computer-printed score and part (possibly final drafts); spiral-bound copies of manuscript score and part (Box 8, Folder 3)
          - —Heft II; computer-printed score and part (possibly final drafts); 2 spiral-bound copies of manuscript of score and part, some with corrections (Box 8, Folder 4)
          - —Heft I; manuscripts of score and part and photocopies with some corrections (Box 8, Folder 5)
          - —Heft II; manuscripts of score and part with some corrections, and photocopies (Box 8, Folder 6)
          - —Heft III; manuscripts of cello part (Box 8, Folder 7)
          - —Hefte l-lll; further draft manuscripts, photocopies and computer-printed copies with corrections (Box 8, Folder 8)
          - —Hefte l-ll; manuscripts, photocopies, and computer-printed copies of working drafts with corrections (Box 8, Folder 9)
          - —Hefte l-ll; manuscripts, photocopies, and computer-printed copies of working drafts with corrections (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - Solo/Chamber ensemble. Original works (Box 9)
          - “Sonata for Piano”, Jun. 18, 1970: 2 manuscript copies, and photocopy with corrections in red (Box 9, Folder 1)
          - “Structure No. 1 in G”, [n.d.]: for cello and piano; manuscript in pencil of cello part (Box 9, Folder 2)
          - “Sommerrain bei Märklins = Summer Rain”, Jun. 12,1999: lead sheet; incomplete manuscript (Box 9, Folder 3)
          - ‘Theme for a Film”, Oct. 3, 1984: lead sheet; manuscript (Box 9, Folder 4)
          - ‘Three for Two: Duos for Bassoon and Violoncello”, May 24,1994-Apr. 26,1995: movements: It Takes Two to Tango - Fishin’ - Not Really th’ Boogie; manuscript, two unbound computer-printed copies with corrections, spiral-bound computer-printed copy (Box 9, Folder 5)
          - ‘Three poems: from Chamber Music by James Joyce”, [n.d]: “No. 1”, for trumpet, horn, English horn, and unidentified bass instrument; manuscript of sketches in pencil (Box 9, Folder 6)
          - ‘Trio for Clarinet, Cello, and Piano”, [1954]: for clarinet in A; manuscripts of score and parts, loose photocopy of score and parts with corrections in pencil and blue pen, comb-bound photocopy of score, spiral-bound photocopy of score and cello part, computer-printed copy of violin I part (arr. from clarinet) for Part Three with bowings in pencil (Box 9, Folder 7)
          - ‘Trumpet Voluntary for Julia and Steve”, May 27, 1997: for three trumpets; manuscript (Box 9, Folder 8)
          - “T.U.B.A. Canon”, Apr. 27, 1975: for two tubas; two photocopies of manuscript (Box 9, Folder 9)
          - “Tubossa”, Apr. 14-Jun. 18, 1983: for tuba and piano; nearly complete manuscript of score, comb-bound photocopy of score; this work was later arranged for tuba and concert band (Box 9, Folder 10)
          - “When Tubas Waltz”, Dec. 26-30, 1973: scherzo-trio for tuba ensemble (two euphoniums and two tubas); manuscript of score (Box 9, Folder 11)
          - “When Cellos Waltz”, May 8, 1991: for four cellos; manuscript of score, 2 photocopies of score and parts, some with corrections, computer-printed copies of score and cello 1 part (Box 9, Folder 12)
          - “When Bartles & Jones Waltz”, Nov. 1, 1991: for string quartet; manuscript of score and photocopies of parts (Box 9, Folder 13)
          - “When Canadians Waltz”, Jan. 25, 1993: for trumpet, flugelhorn, horn, trombone, and tuba; manuscript of score and parts (Box 9, Folder 14)
          - “When Tubalogists Waltz”, Aug. 30, 1998-Jan. 23, 1999: for 3 euphoniums and 3 tubas; manuscript of score (Box 9, Folder 15)
          - ‘The NEW When Tubas Waltz”, [n.d.]: for 3 euphoniums and 3 tubas; appears to be the same arrangement as When Tubalogists Waltz; computer-printed copy of score and parts (Box 9, Folder 16)
          - ‘The Wind”, Oct. 30-Nov. 26, 1983: for cello and piano; manuscript of score and part, corrected photocopy of part (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - Solo/Chamber ensemble. Original works (Box 10)
          - “Air from the 3rd Orchestral Suite”, copyright 2001: for cello and piano; by J. S. Bach, arr. and edited by Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript with unrealized accompaniment of score and part; manuscript with realized accompaniment; photocopy of reference Bach score (Box 10, Folder 1)
          - “Amer. Christmas Carols”, [n.d.]: for cello; manuscript and photocopy with fingerings on cello part; consists of melodies of various Christmas carols popular in North America, if not all American in origin (Box 10, Folder 2)
          - “Familiar Melodies from the Notebooks of Leopold Mozart and Anna Magdalena Bach for Beginning Cellists (Two-Part Settings to be Played with or without Piano Accompaniment) in First Closed Position = Bekannte Melodien aus den Notenheften von Leopold Mozart und Anna Magdalena Bach für beginninde Cellisten (zweistimmige Sätze zum Spielen mit oder ohne Klavierbegleitung) in der ersten engen Lage”, [1990?]: arranged and edited by Alfred H. Bartles; consists of 12 pieces; includes versions for cello and piano, and for two cellos; manuscript and corrected photocopy of piano/cello version, manuscript of two-cello version (with corrections from Jan. 25, 1990) and partially corrected photocopy (Box 10, Folder 3)
          - “Roumanian Folk Dances”, Feb. 20-Mar. 30, 1993: by Bêla Bartok, transcribed for brass quintet by Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score; computer-printed copy of parts (Box 10, Folder 4)
          - “Roumanian Folk Dances”, Feb. 9-14,1986: by Bêla Bartok, transcribed for tuba and piano by Alfred H. Bartles; manuscript of score and part; with two published reference models for piano solo and cello with piano (Luigi Silva) (Box 10, Folder 5)
          - “Sonata V”, Feb. 20, 1986: for cello and piano; by Benedetto Marcello, arranged and edited by Alfred H. Bartles; incomplete manuscripts of score and part and partially notated photocopy of score (Box 10, Folder 6)
          - “Star Child Music”, [n.d.]: by E. Pracht; possibly incomplete parts, only violin I, violin II, and viola extant (Box 10, Folder 7)
          - “Adagio e Tarantella”, Jun. 7,1984: for cello and piano; by G. Goltermann, [edited by] A. H. Bartles; manuscript of cello part with fingerings; partially completed manuscript of score; photocopy of printed reference model score (Box 10, Folder 8)
          - “Wachet auf, ruft uns die Stimme”, Sept. 21, 1971: for cello and organ; by J. S. Bach, transcribed by A. H. Bartles; manuscript of score and part (Box 10, Folder 9)
          - “Weihnacht im Unterricht: Cellospiel in Gruppen (zweistimmig und dreistimmig gesetzte Weihnachtslieder) in der ersten, zum größten Teil engen Lage”, [n.d.]: for two or three cellos; arranged by Alfred H. Bartles; consists of 17 pieces; manuscript of score (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Series A: Musical compositions—Manuscripts
    - Subseries 1: Single works
      - Subsubseries 3: Vocal works
        - Vocal works. Original works (Box 11)
          - “Advent”, Dec. 9-23, 2003: for voice and piano; text by Rainer Maria Rilke; manuscript and photocopy (Box 11, Folder 1)
          - “Age After Age”, copyright 1964: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alf Bartles; ozalid photocopy (Box 11, Folder 2)
          - “And Well I Shall Be There...”, [1978]: for SATB choir and strings; text by Juanita de Long; manuscript of score and bound ozalid photocopy (Box 11, Folder 3)
          - “Buon Giorno Napoli”, copyright 1965: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; 2 manuscripts, 1 with address stapled (Box 11, Folder 4)
          - “Cabo Frió”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 5)
          - “Child Jesu”, Nov. 21-28, 1966: for SATB with piano; text by Hans Christian Andersen; manuscript and comb-bound photocopy (Box 11, Folder 6)
          - “A Christmas Wish”, Jan. 31, 1997: lead sheet; by Beegie Adair and Alfred Bartles; manuscript of lead sheet with corrected photocopy, manuscript of lead sheet with realized accompaniment (?Jul. 16, 1998), manuscript of incomplete lead sheet (Dec. 27, 1984) (Box 11, Folder 7)
          - “Come Ride the Wind with Me”, Jan. 19, 1964: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Bart Howell [pseudonym of Alfred H. Bartles]; manuscript with realized accompaniment (Box 11, Folder 8)
          - “Drei Weihnachts Wiegenlieder”, Dec. 4,1969-Jan. 21, 1970: for soprano and piano; movements: Child Jesus / text by Hans Christian Andersen - Sweet was the Song / text by John Hay - He Is Sleeping / Polish 16th century carol; manuscript and photocopy with corrections (Box 11, Folder 9)
          - “Farewell to Firenze”, copyright 1964: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred H. Bartles; ozalid photocopy of manuscript with pencil additions (Box 11, Folder 10)
          - “A Giving Heart”, (ca. 2004?): for voice and piano; text by Robert L. Lynn; uncompleted manuscript; includes copies of poems and letter from the poet (Box 11, Folder 11)
          - “I Looked for Me”, copyright 1968: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred H. Bartles; lead sheet and manuscript with realized accompaniment (Box 11, Folder 12)
          - “I’m Surprised at You”, copyright 1965: lead sheet; by Rae Moore, Bryan Lindsay, and Alf Bartles; manuscript with penciled-in lyrics (Box 11, Folder 13)
          - “Invisible Man”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript with partially realized accompaniment and photocopy (Box 11, Folder 14)
          - “Love, We Have Scaled the Heights”, Jun. 18,1981: for mezzo-soprano and piano; text by Basil Payne; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 15)
          - “Miss Amanda Lee”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; “An Odor of Verbena” scratched out; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 16)
          - “Never Trust a Friend”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Mundy Snow and Barton Howell [pseudonyms of Bryan Lindsay and Alfred H. Bartles]; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 17)
          - “New York Bound”, copyright 1964: by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript with typed lyrics (Box 11, Folder 18)
          - “No One Told Me”, copyright 1964: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript with partially realized accompaniment and typed lyrics (Box 11, Folder 19)
          - “October”, Oct. 28, 1956: for soprano and piano; text by Siegfried Finser; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 20)
          - “One Day Late in May”, copyright 1964: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript, and holograph copy with partially realized accompaniment (Box 11, Folder 21)
          - “Right Back Where I Started”, copyright 1964: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay, Alf Bartles; manuscript with pencil corrections (Box 11, Folder 22)
          - “Ring Out Wild Bells”, Dec. 7-9, 1969: for SATB and piano; text by Alfred Lord Tennyson; manuscript of score, photocopy of score with corrections, manuscripts of vocal parts (SA, T, B) (Box 11, Folder 23)
          - “S’il vous plaît”, [n.d.]: by Alfred Bartles and Bryan Lindsay; manuscript with realized accompaniment (Box 11, Folder 24)
          - “Sleepy Summer Solitude”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 25)
          - “Tears (In a Plastic Bag)”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 26)